<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nubificus Ltd</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Nubificus Ltd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kata-containers: sandboxing container workloads for security and efficiency</title><link>/news/news10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news10/</guid><description>Anastassios Nanos delivered an insightful presentation at OpenInfra Days Hungary, in Budapest, earlier this June, highlighting the innovative capabilities of the Kata Containers project. The talk focused on the project&amp;rsquo;s advancements, particularly the introduction and maturity of the Rust runtimes, alongside the go version of the runtime, and demonstrated how the Kata team is leveraging these technologies to enhance the performance and security of serverless workloads. As a first time Architecture Committee member since April 2024, Dr Nanos presented the current status of the project, and how the team at Nubificus &amp;amp; Nubis is using kata-containers to sandbox serverless workloads, while exposing hardware acceleration capabilities by integrating vAccel to the container runtime.</description></item><item><title>vAccel v0.6 is out!</title><link>/news/news9/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news9/</guid><description>Nubificus LTD proudly presents the latest release of the vAccel framework. vAccel v0.6.0 is available, as well as a hot fix followup for x86_64, aarch64, and armv7l architectures, with the essential binaries for users to get started.
A major addition to our previous release is Torch support. Users are now able to run inference on Torch models seamlessly, on local and remote targets (CPU/GPU etc.). A short screen cast is available to check torch with vAccel in action!</description></item><item><title>FOSDEM 2024</title><link>/news/news8/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news8/</guid><description>FOSDEM 2024 was a blast! Our team was there presenting our work around unikernels, and their interaction with the cloud-native world.
The first presentation took place in the Containers devroom, where we described the challenges of securing containers within VM or microVM sandboxes and the complexities of resource optimization on physical nodes. We presented urunc, a CRI-compatible container runtime spawning unikernels packaged in OCI images. The talk highlighted urunc&amp;rsquo;s internals, covering hypervisor support, network and storage handling, and integration with high-level orchestration frameworks like Kubernetes, while also addressing network setup implications when combining unikernels and generic containers in a k8s context.</description></item><item><title>SERRANO Project Concludes with Nubificus LTD laying the ground for Interoperable Hardware Acceleration and Secure Application Deployment</title><link>/news/news7/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news7/</guid><description>The SERRANO H2020 research project, a collaborative effort led by ICCS&amp;lsquo; High Speed Communication Networks Lab, successfully concludes, marking a significant breakthrough in various aspects of cloud- and edge-based computing technologies. The project aimed to introduce a novel ecosystem spanning application deployment software components, to systems software enabling the use of specialized hardware resources.
One of the key achievements of the SERRANO project is the work carried out by Nubificus LTD in enabling interoperable hardware acceleration using vAccel.</description></item><item><title>Nubificus LTD at Open Source Summit Europe 2023</title><link>/news/news6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news6/</guid><description>Sep 18th-21st we were in Bilbao, Spain for the Open Source Summit Europe 2023! We had the opportunity to talk about open-source, meet friends, and make new ones!
It was a pleasure for us to present our work on bringing unikernels closer to the cloud-native world! Video Slides
In this session, we went through the options that users have to deploy applications in Cloud &amp;amp; Edge environments. We talked about containers, sandboxed containers, and unikernels, introduced our own container runtime tailored to unikernels, and presented the integration effort we have undertaken to allow unikernels to execute in k8s &amp;amp; Serverless Computing frameworks.</description></item><item><title>Unikraft Hackathon</title><link>/news/news5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news5/</guid><description>We are excited to host a Unikraft Hackathon in Athens, GR! It is a great opportunity for students, professionals and systems software enthousiasts to meet, exchange ideas, and code together in this two-day event!
Nubificus LTD, along with the Unikraft community, the High Speed Communication Networks Lab (HSCN) and the Computing Systems Lab (CSLab) of the National Technical University of Athens (ICCS/NTUA) come together to organize the Unikraft Athens Hackathon to be held on Thursday and Friday, March 30-31, 2023.</description></item><item><title>vAccel v0.5.0 is out!</title><link>/news/news4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news4/</guid><description>Nubificus LTD proudly presents the latest release of the vAccel framework. vAccel v0.5.0 is available as a tar bundle for x86_64 and aarch64 architectures, with the essential binaries for users to get started.
Additionally, the individual components are packaged as binary artifacts or deb packages for users to install them directly. For a list of the binary components please visit vAccel&amp;rsquo;s documentation page. The core vAccel library is open-source, available on github.</description></item><item><title>The 2022 Innovation Radar praises Nubificus&#39; work on Serverless Computing</title><link>/news/news3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news3/</guid><description>Nubificus LTD has been identified by the European Commission&amp;rsquo;s Innovation Radar as a high potential innovator for their work on Serverless computing. Specifically, EC&amp;rsquo;s IR identified the Serverless Framework that Nubificus LTD develops as having a high potential for innovation. The lightweight serverless framework for the Edge is being developed as part of the 5G-COMPLETE Horizon 2020-funded project.
The framework to provide Fast, Secure &amp;amp; Efficient Serverless for the Edge was assessed by the IR (https://www.</description></item><item><title>EU Project Manager (EPMR)</title><link>/jobs/job6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jobs/job6/</guid><description>Responsibilities:
Plan and organize project activities, perform risk management and propose contingency measures and adaptations to achieve project goals Directly implement projects’ activities such as organizing field research, drafting studies/reports/deliverables, planning &amp;amp; organizing events, etc., according to the project needs, as well as financial and human resources limitations Coordinate the implementation of projects’ tasks when assigned to project partners and/or colleagues ensuring final delivery Ensure comprehensive and up-to-date project documentation Contribute to new project ideas generation and development opportunities.</description></item><item><title>DevOps Engineer (DER)</title><link>/jobs/job7/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jobs/job7/</guid><description>Responsibilities:
Define and set development, test, release, update, and support processes for the product and service offerings. Implement and set up development, testing, automation tools, and IT infrastructure. Plan the team structure, activities, and participate in project management activities Monitor the processes during the entire lifecycle for its adherence and update or create new processes for improvement. Encourage and build automated processes wherever possible Evaluate / select / build and deploy appropriate CI/CD tools Requirements:</description></item><item><title>Senior Systems Software Engineer (SSSER)</title><link>/jobs/job1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jobs/job1/</guid><description>Responsibilities:
Develop software and research for a cutting edge technology project Design and develop reusable and reliable code using at least one of the following: C / Python / GO / C++ / Rust Partake in all aspects of the project’s life cycle Research and solve complex engineering challenges Lead a small team of engineers and coordinate effort to achieve short-term goals Lead upstreaming efforts to contribute to open-source projects Communicate the team&amp;rsquo;s findings &amp;amp; results to company&amp;rsquo;s partners Requirements:</description></item><item><title>Software Engineer (SER)</title><link>/jobs/job3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jobs/job3/</guid><description>Responsibilities:
Develop software for a cutting edge technology project Design and develop reusable and reliable code using at least one of the following: C / Python / GO / C++ / Rust Participate in upstreaming efforts to contribute to open-source projects Requirements:
Minimum 3 years of experience in software development BSc or MSc degree in Computer Science/Engineering, Telecommunications or similar Good understanding of best practices in software development Working knowledge of control systems like git Familiarity with container runtimes and orchestrators (Kubernetes) Proficiency in spoken and written English Ability to work in a distributed team Location:</description></item><item><title>Nubificus LTD enables efficient &amp; secure execution at the edge</title><link>/news/news2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news2/</guid><description>Nubificus LTD participates in the ICT-40-2020 SERRANO Project (H2020 GA No 101017168): Transparent Application Deployment in a Secure, Accelerated and Cognitive Cloud Continuum, which kicked off in January 2021 and will last three years. SERRANO consortium consists of 11 partners from industry and academia. SERRANO investigates the transparent deployment of applications in a secure and accelerated infrastructure of edge, cloud and HPC resources, based on FPGAs, GPUs, Virtual Platforms and Smart NICs, while facilitating their automated and cognitive orchestration.</description></item><item><title>Systems Software Engineer (SSER)</title><link>/jobs/job2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/jobs/job2/</guid><description>Responsibilities:
Develop software for a cutting edge technology project Design and develop reusable and reliable code using at least one of the following: C / Python / GO / C++ / Rust Participate in upstreaming efforts to contribute to open-source projects Requirements:
Minimum 3 years of experience in software development BSc or MSc degree in Computer Science/Engineering, Telecommunications or similar Good understanding of best practices in software development Working knowledge of control systems like git Experience with virtualization environments and containers Proficiency in spoken and written English Ability to work in a distributed team Location:</description></item><item><title>vAccel now available on Firecracker</title><link>/news/news1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/news1/</guid><description>Today, Nubificus LTD introduced vAccel support on AWS Firecracker, opening the door for enabling hardware acceleration for serverless computing.
With a slim design and precise abstractions, vAccel semantically exposes hardware acceleration features to users with little to no knoweldge of software acceleration framework internals.
Serverless computing workflows are now able to enjoy compute-offload mechanisms to provide AI/ML services as functions, triggered thousands or millions of times by events, on-demand, auto-scaling to multiple physical and virtual nodes.</description></item></channel></rss>